KAYRA ALAT

18 Wagtail Grove Cheltenham GL52 8GZ 07478732852 KayraAlat@gmail.com

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Professionally I care about one thing: helping people by solving their problems. Predominantly I do this with code, but the real world isn't so one dimensional. I make sure I understand the entire ecosystem, from idea inception, through the architectural process, the coding implementation and even deployment concerns. This allows me to see the entire picture and design the correct solution, unencumbered by the chains of specialisation.

SKILLS

Python (Django, Flask), HTML, CSS/Sass (Bootstrap, Skeleton), Javascript (jQuery, Angular), PHP (Drupal, WordPress), C# (MVC), SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL, multiple ORMs), Linux (CentOS and Ubuntu), version control (Git, TFS), Bash scripting and design tools (Photoshop, Sketch). I also speak Turkish.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

May 2015 - Present | Python Freelance and Personal Projects

- Building applications from the ground up has given me a deeper understanding of the entire process, placing me in the position to make informed decisions about every aspect of a project.
- Working with clients directly taught me how to perfectly prioritise features based on commercial needs.
- I also learned how to communicate in a way that is simultaneously easy to understand, and places the client in a position where they are able to make decisions that are informed by my technical expertise.

June 2014 - May 2015 | PHP Developer at Redweb

- Working as part of a new team meant defining workflows and procedures. I made sure
 every decision was well thought out, fully documented and easy to comprehend.
- I took the time to ensure that other members of the team fully understood the reasons behind each decision. This was to assist with critical thinking when difficult decisions needed to be made, especially ones that went against procedures as is sometimes necessary when things don't go to plan.
- When working on client projects I was involved in every stage of the process, from the initial design decisions to the more familiar technical specifications and deployment strategies.
- I care deeply about the applications I work on, and made sure my technical knowledge was available for all relevant decisions, resulting in the best possible outcome for not only the final product, but a smooth implementation of the solution.

September 2012 - August 2013 | .Net Developer Placement at Redweb

- My primary goal was to create applications to be used internally by employees to improve workflows.
- This involved liaising with the heads of different departments to discover choke points of monotonous manual work that could be alleviated with software.
- The application I am most proud is an analysis tool. It crawls websites and analyses their content to inform the SEO team of whether or not it is worth approaching the owners for potential work.
- This was previously achieved by manually parsing HTML; creating the application required me to distil the technical expertise of the team into logical code.

EDUCATION

2010 - 2014 | Bournemouth University

Bachelor of Science in Computing

2007 - 2009 | Cheltenham Bournside School Sixth Form Centre

A-Levels in Maths, Physics, Computing and an AS-Level in Psychology

2005 - 2007 | Cheltenham Bournside School

Ten GCSEs with A-C grade including Maths and Science

MENTORING AND TEACHING

Peer Assisted Learning (PAL) at Bournemouth University

This paid position involved helping other students in the lower years with their assignments and upcoming tests. I made sure that a completed assignment or great test score was a by-product of a complete understanding of the course materials, rather than simply teaching them how to comply with the university mark scheme.

Peer Mentoring at Bournside Sixth Form Centre

I held the responsibility of helping students in lower school who were experiencing problems at home or at school, and I learned the drawbacks of superficial solutions. I found that teaching them how to solve their own problems resulted in much happier students. However these deeper solutions needed to be hard won with critical thinking.

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

I regularly attend hack events. I find the different way of working opens my mind to new possibilities that I otherwise wouldn't have considered. I also enjoy meeting new people and learning from them; I take great pleasure in the unique challenge of collaborating with people I have never met before.

Due to my love of food I thought it would be a good idea to take up fitness, and soon found myself enjoying it despite years of school induced disdain. I regularly run, cycle, visit the gym and practice martial arts, however I also enjoy rock climbing, gymnastics, juggling, swimming and windsurfing.

References available upon request.